Profile

Experienced in logistics and supply chain industries with over nine years of experience providing clients and company holding responsibility for receiving, inspecting, inventorying, loading, storing, delivering and installation supplies and equipment. Prepare supply documents using automated supply system for accounting of non-expendable and durable supplies and equipment, also maintaining 100% accountability of supplies and equipment. Managed the loading, unloading and moving stock using equipment such as forklifts and reach trucks. Maintained proper records management for incoming and outgoing stock.

Career Objective

To secure challenging career in logistics industry which allows me to exercise my potential to the fullest and provide me with opportunities to improve my skill set and advance my career.

Languages	Proficiency (Best = 10 - Worst = 1)	
	<u>Spoken</u>	<u>Written</u>
English	10	9
Tamil	10	8
Mandarin	3	0
Malay	8	5

Personal Attributes

- Excellent communication skills and teamwork spirit
- Resourceful, independent, meticulous, coordinated and possess a positive attitude
- Able to quickly adapt to new environments
- Willing to learn and take up new opportunities
- A committed, dedicated and responsible team player who is able to motivate others in the team
- To deliver results in the shortest time possible
- Able to work multitask n work under pressure

Education

Hong Dao Primary School

1990-1996 PSLE

Yio Chu Kang Secondary School

1997-2000 'N' Levels

Technical & IT Skills

Office Automations Tools : MS Excels, MS Powerpoint, MS Words

Multimedia Tools : Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Lightroom, Adobe illustrator, Adobe XD

Driving Licence

Class 2/3/4/5: **Yes**

Forklift : **YES** (Certificate C0064-05)

Skills & Abilities

MANAGEMENT

• Managed and secured logistics of the warehouse product. Evaluated operational records and made scheduling adjustments to maximize efficiency. Resolved service issues in a timely manner including coordinating and processing returns.

COMMUNICATION

 Liaison between warehouse/technical support staff and finance department to coordinate data entry including SAP to create new RMA's. Coordinate with all non-warranty, non-direct customer RMA's. Worked closely with the Finance and Sales departments.

LEADERSHIP

Provided leadership and coaching for a staff of 16 receiving and warehouse associates. Trained
employees in warehouse operations, safety procedures, company policy-ensured compliance with
all regulation and internal safety guidelines. Assigned tasks and overlook team's performance to
ensure productivity standards were maintained. Coordinate and supervise inventory counts.

Work Experience

SINGAPORE ZOOLOGICAL GARDEN | ZOO KEEPER | FEB 2004 - MAR 2006

- Keeping animal enclosures clean, germ-free and safe secured
- Preparing food such as pellets, fresh produce, meat or hay and administer medications
- Observing animals and check for any signs of distress or ill health. Designing, building and repairing environments which are close to natural habitats as possible

- Coming up with creative ideas for enrichment to keep animals active and interested in their environment
- Educating visitors by sharing our animal knowledge through demonstrations with live animals, talk, tours and visitor experiences
- Keeping daily detailed records of behavior, eating habits, births, deaths and other events. Training animal behavior to make feeding, medicating and monitoring easy and safe

SENIOR CARGO ASSISTANT | AREOHUB CHANGI CARGO COMPLEX) | APRIL 2006 – MAY 2008

- Plan the loading of the cargo products into ULDs/Bulk for carriage on the assigned aircraft in accordance with the priorities given, to achieve optimum utilization of capacity
- Liaise with handling agent for flight operational requirements and coordination of activities for transshipments
- Check that the cargo is loaded as specified in the load plan and to ensure that the safety of the aircraft is not compromised and the product quality standards are maintained
- Ensured bookings are made in SFIV system and shipments flown as booked/planned
- Assist in resolving claims and discrepancies liaising with concerned authorities and departments
- Perform delegated tasks, administrative, operational and promotional which will enhance profitability
- Complete administrative duties as directed by the cargo supervisor/officer, including data entry, statistics and reports
- Provide operational support and cover operational duties as directed by the cargo supervisor/officer e.g. freighter
- Lead a team of 15

LOGISTICS SUPERVISOR | THIONG NAM LOGISTICS | JUNE 2008 - MAY 2012

- Ensure that goods are shipped and delivered in a timely manner and that inventory levels are sufficiently maintained
- Oversee the transportation of products from one location to another, such as from locking docks to warehouses or warehouse to stores.
- Arrange product pickups and deliveries with transportation companies and route drivers accordingly
- Contact cost analysis of several transportation companies in order to select one that is costefficient and able to handle the shipment loads
- Contacting various transportation companies to get shipping quotes and deciding on the best carriers based on cost, availability and reliability
- Communicate with trucking companies, warehouse supervisors, customs brokers, sales department and customers to ensure that all parties are working together to guarantee that shipments are packed, sent and delivered in timely manner
- Manage inventory and analyze to keep certain items in stock
- Responsible for re-ordering product as needed to maintain sufficient inventory levels
- Meeting short deadlines and lead a team to work together to achieve the goal
- Managing and leading a team of 12

TRANSPORT COODINATOR | AARON TRANSPORT | JUNE 2012 - MAY 2014

- To ensure the smooth running of the allocated transport shift activity, ensuring appropriate resources (people, equipment) are available to meet planned activity levels.
- Ensure compliance to all relevant legislation affecting transport operations
- Maintain and enhance effective working relationships with staff and drivers
- Ensure staff works to the processes and procedures relating to the transport operations
- Assist in the recruitment of driving staff as required
- Regular communication with drivers and driver attandents on transport operations
- And to ensure all operational transports are well maintained and sent to regular servicing

WHARF OPERATIONS SUPERVISOR | SEAFRONT SUPPORT COMPANY | MAY 2014 - MAY 2019

- Supervision of workers involved in ship operations
- Handling vessel hatch covers
- Handling selective discharging / loading of containers
- Guiding quay crane (SQC) in gantry travel
- Assist with technician in changing quay crane spreader
- Fixing / removing OH frame / chains
- Sorting out types and classifications of containers
- Stowing, identification and numbering system
- Yard layout and addressing systems
- Handling container handling equipment
- Overseeing lashing / unleashing operations
- Handling of operations documents
- Communication with shipping traffic assistant and quay crane operator via radio set (Walkie-Talkie)
- Signalling for UC operations
- Handling of reefer containers
- Handling of vessel berthing / unberthing operations
- Handling safety requirements at container terminals and quay side
- Accident case studies
- Maintaining workplace safety and health act
- Handling OJT personnals at container terminal

DRIVER | MLS | JUNE 2019 - OCT 2020

- Sorting of air freight cargos
- Clearance of cargos at terminal customs
- Delivery of cargo/goods to customers
- Ensure to maintain proper road safety and regulations
- Receiving cargo and goods from customers

PRIME MOVER DRIVER | POSAN TRANSPORTION | OCT 2019 - JAN 2022

- Trucking of container from/to customers location
- Trucking of container from/to PSA terminals
- Ensure containers are in good condition upon receiving it

Hobbies

- Photography
- Fishing
- Trekking
- Mountain biking
- Diving
- Billard
- Soccer
- Video Gaming

Expected Salary

\$2600 - \$3000

Able To Start

With Immediate Effect